hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski in this podcast I talk
about how coaches trainers mentors
speakers and non-fiction authors can
reach more paid clients in mentorship
membership coaching or online course
businesses and how to be able to make
six figures it's over $100,000 a year or
even seven figures that's a
multi-million dollar income serving
other people helping others without
having to burn out and spend hours and
hours and hours doing it yourself okay
how to move out of the one-on-one
coaching grind and into a group or
membership model where you basically get
paid by each member each month and you
can scale infinitely we've scaled these
businesses to thousands of clients and
generated tens of millions of dollars
per year with these same business models
I've been doing this in the this
industry for over 21 years successfully
working with some of the top most
financially successful trainers and
mentors and in my own business we've
generated multiple seven figures over
the last year and a half and I want to
show you how you can be successful
yourself this podcast is your gateway to
being able to reach the results that you
want most people struggle with this
because they're not willing to actually
look at the hard things and one of the
hard things that people don't actually
look at it's actually that what makes
you the most financially successful as a
coach trainer or Mentor somebody who
sells courses has a membership has a
coaching program basically if you fall
into any of the categories that I just
mentioned right now this is for you okay
and if you're struggling to make the
kind of money that you want to make
maybe you're not bringing in six figures
well really my goal is I want you I want
to get you to multiple six figures half
a million to a million dollar a year and
that is going to revolutionize and
transform your life okay some of youall
might be like well I'm just starting out
I'm little old me I'm not sure if I
could do that I promise you this you can
now of course you're going to have to do
the hard things is it guaranteed that
you're going to get there just by
listening to this podcast episode no
that would be crazy to even promise
something like that but if you're
willing to figure out what is not
working what needs to change you can be
successful one of the biggest areas that
I notice with coaches trainers and
mentors that I talk to that I work with
that are on my social media that are in
my coaching
groups is the need to do everything
right now of course Excellence Integrity
honesty so important kindness compassion
impacting people but the problem
is sometimes times the values that you
have are preventing you from making the
kind of money that you want to make and
moving into a group coaching business
because you have certain values that are
immovable certain con
convictions that you feel oh I
can't not do these things certain things
that are have such a tight grip on your
behavior and beliefs that's actually
stopping you from being able to create
the kind of income that you want to make
you know one of those is this one that I
I hear
often from many of the coaches trainers
and mentors that I have is well I just
don't have any time to not be making
money and I got to I got to fill in
every blank space in my life that I have
with productive hours of time can I tell
you this giving yourself time for
guilt-free play is one of the most
positive things that you can do and it
goes go against quote unquote the right
way to do things that you're preached at
on social media there's productivity
experts that are telling you to stop
wasting time and how to not do so when
in fact all they're doing is serving a
disregulated emotional response that
often comes in from trauma that makes
you feel like I can't relax and I have
to stay on all the time and I have to
stay hyper vigilent and make sure that
I'm always productive or I'm a failure
and you tie your identity to your
productivity I dealt with this for a
long time and it's an area that I would
actually recommend that you learn how to
unwire inside of yourself to be more
successful and to start to give yourself
more time to play and to have fun
another one is people who value art and
beauty and things that look really
aesthetically pleasing this one's a big
one and I've worked with a lot of great
coaches and mentors that have this
value unfort fortunately in the
beginning before you're making a million
dollars and I really wouldn't even touch
this until you're making 1 to2 million
at all focusing your energy on
aesthetically pleasing websites branding
courses making everything look good is
the worst possible thing that you can do
now you may not agree with me because
you might say well you have different
values than me Jeremiah we're just
different people I mean this with all
due respect but it's one of these single
biggest areas with working with
thousands of coaches and mentors over
the years that I see people cling to so
tightly as well that's just my values
that's just my
personality and those same people don't
make the kind of money that they want to
make they're burnt out working way too
hard to produce very very little because
of the need quote unquote to make things
look super professional I wouldn't worry
about that until you're making at least
a million to $2 million it's not going
to add to your bottom
line and it's only a waste of time that
that energy could be spent on what
actually will produce Financial results
for
you the common thing that I see and I
and I I am it's it's the it's the uh
it's the majority not the minority the
minority there's maybe a 5% outlier that
this isn't the case with but with 95% of
people that I see that have a value for
visually pleasing Aesthetics in their
business is that they don't make the
kind of money that they want to make
until they actually loosen up just a
little bit on that and they stop trying
to make everything perfect and they
actually realize that the words that
they say how they connect with people
online being able to make a connection
with somebody has nothing to do with how
you
look because that's an out W appearance
what matters more is the Deep nature of
that connection that you make and you
can do that with simple words and simple
graphics and images that you do not need
to invest hours and hours and hours into
making things look more visually
appealing and this is one of those areas
that I meet people that they believe
unshakeably is so important to them to
make sure that they get this right
before they can put themselves out there
and
those people the majority do not ever
make the kind of financial income that
they actually want to make and the
potential that they have because they
are letting their values prevent them
from putting themselves out there to
make the kind of money that they want to
make I find that a great sadness and a
great disservice and something that is
really um not a healthy way of
thinking to operate that way
as a business owner you can do that as a
hobby you can do that for fun but not as
a business that pays you fulltime that's
just not responsible in any possible way
whatsoever and so I would recommend this
might be one of the hardest most painful
things that you have to
do is to loosen up just a little bit on
making everything look and appear
perfect here's another one and it's
closely related to this the need for
everything to be complete when they put
it out there I strongly believe in what
we call the alpha release approach to
coaching and training and releasing an
underdevelopment program that you're
still improving on over time instead of
spending all of this energy making
everything a completion before you put
out there I see a lot of people they do
this and it makes me sad because I
talked to them 10 years ago and they
tell me jeremi I'm I'm I'm I'm getting
everything complete before I can launch
it and I talk to them every year for 10
years and they still haven't even made a
little bit of progress because they're
working so hard to make everything
complete and it's this identity of
perfection this identity of I appear
finished I appear done I look good
enough to other people that I see that
stops the potential for making six and
seven figures in most of the coaches and
mentors that I work with
I would rather you start imperfectly
make a ton of money and then refine it
over
time then what I see the alternative is
and this is again the majority not the
minority very small minority maybe it's
not the case the majority that I work
with that I see that do this and operate
in this
way still making everything perfect and
honestly that's just a level of
insecurity because we don't believe in
ourselves enough so we feel that we have
to present ourselves at a certain level
to be worthy of financial
success and that is the biggest lie that
I see that coaches trainers and mentors
believe another one closely related that
is I have to be this top level
top-of-the Mountain best ever expert
before I'm ever good enough to put my
information out
there what if you launched something
that you got done in a weekend on a land
page that looks good but it's not like
you know you hired a million dooll team
that did it it looks good enough to
connect with people maybe you don't know
100% of what your next five courses are
going to be but you got something ready
to get in front of people and that might
make you feel anxious to even think
about it being incomplete to put out
there I want you to challenge what are
you trying to avoid why do you feel the
need to make everything so perfect in
your life before you can put it out
there answer that question and realize
that this behavior that pressure that
you're putting on yourself is preventing
you from making the kind of money that
you could possibly make but you are
making decisions that are entirely
opposed to being able to make the kind
of finances that you want by operating
that way and I see this more common more
often than not very few people can even
go here mentally with me they feel like
it's just way too much to even loosen up
on their perfectionism to loosen up on
their need to make everything just so
before they put it out there and it
often comes from the need to not
disappoint other people and to have
people be approved of them and if it's
not that then it's a high level of
Excellence that actually goes into an
unrealistic personal expectation of
Pride and ego that you have to be a
certain way in order to be good enough
to put yourself out there and many times
that is a form of judgment both towards
ourselves and others who maybe don't
measure up to what we think is good
enough for them to put themselves out
there I'm touching on a lot of stuff
that quite frankly a lot of people
disagree with me on but the ones who I
meet that are financially successful in
this business do agree on it that you
have to take action there's actually a
book that I read called two weeks notice
by Amy Porterfield one of the top
mentors and authors that's out there
that teaches this type of stuff as well
and she is a
self-proclaimed Perfection visual
aesthetic
lover and yet she also recommends the
same thing I just said to you and I love
that she says this don't even concern
yourself with the kind of energy to put
behind making things look perfect until
you're actually making the kind of money
that you want to make because it will
only serve to prevent you from being
successful there's enough that you need
to do of other than all this stuff that
doesn't matter and so I would recommend
here's what I see most coaches and
mentors do is that let's say that this
is the visual of all the stuff that they
could do in their business but this is
the stuff that's actually going to make
them money most of the time most of the
coaches and mentors that I see do all
the stuff that really does not
contribute to their bottom line at all
because of how it makes them look to
others and they're still not making any
money and they maybe do a sliver of what
makes them
money and I would just say let's
allocate a large portion of all this
energy spent doing all this that does
not contribute to the money and fill
that up over here and focus a concerted
effort on what's going to produce
profits and maybe just back off a little
bit on the perfectionism till you get
something out there that's actually
bringing in clients and this process of
imperfect action is the number one
process that I have seen that has
created wealth
for the coaches mentors and trainers
that I've worked
with the ones who are actually
successful and so what I find is it
really is only merely arrogance and
pride that won't allow us to do this or
a deep-seated traumatic fear of
disappointing
others both of those are not healthy and
they're not going to help you be
financially
successful you have to
learn that
losing business first off is a good
thing if you lose clients because quote
unquote you're not good enough to other
people and they walk away from you quote
unquote because they're disappointed or
they don't think that you're at a
pristine level that loss of income is a
good thing those are people that are not
actually worth you working with and the
amount of energy that it's going to take
to work with them is
astronomically detrimental to your
business and that's not an
exaggeration it's better to repel those
people and to focus in on the ones who
really can connect with you instead of
clinging so tightly to I got to do all
these things in order for people to buy
from me I got to do all these things to
get them to trust me and all this I'm
sorry but most of the stuff that people
are doing that they think is required
and the amount of time that they think
that it needs to take to build their
business is the very stuff that will
never make them a dime of
income start doing the stuff that's
going to make you money and then start
adding more of this other stuff people
do it in reverse all the time why
because this stuff's comfortable this
stuff feels like wisdom when it's the
most possibly unwise thing you can do
even if those are your values in other
parts of life even if you have
convictions in your whole ident identity
that Perfection and beauty and
Excellence or how you do everything this
framework of
operating will not produce results for
you until you focus in with Excellence
on what is going to produce
finances and then you start adding in
some of the more aesthetic stuff later
and that my friends will take you to
Heights that you never imagined the
other alternative
I rarely ever see those people for
longer than a year or two and they're
just as frustrated a year later but
they're stuck on their need to make
everything just
perfect and it makes me sad to see this
way of operating that people operate in
I'd rather see them
succeed you don't need to struggle as
hard as you're
struggling you don't need to be working
as hard as you feel you need to do you
don't need to do all the stuff that you
need to do the process for success in
this business is actually very simple
but the hardest part is learning that I
might need to unlearn and stop doing
stuff that I feel is required and that I
might even feel I need to do because of
my values temporarily in order to
produce the financial results that are
going to bring in cash flow for your
business this is a controversial topic
and I have a lot of people who once I
say it the way that I just said it
they're like no I can't make money more
important than my values Jeremiah I
can't make money more important than my
values you're you're missing the point
completely I never said that I said that
it might just be about prioritizing what
order to do things
in and that will help you produce the
most authentic ethical and best business
you could ever imagine and I can't wait
to see what happens and comes out of
this those of you that are still
listening you have ears to hear you're
willing to hear this I guarantee you
there are people who turned off this
episode 10 minutes into it because it
was just man I just I can't make money
that
important Jeremiah why you so Money
Motivated all the time why you always
talking about money people say this to
me because when you start bringing in
cash flow in your business everything
else solves it itself all your problems
and frustrations that you have in your
business are solved by increasing cas
cash flow and this is not about burnout
this is not about working thousands of
hours or or killing yourself or grinding
to produce results actually the way that
I mapped out here that you shouldn't do
is as a
grind the way that I'm talking about is
actually very simple it's the fastest
simplest least amount of hours to put in
and produces the best results it
actually produces the best results for
the client
and will actually produce the best
results results to your
reputation in the long run you may have
people in the beginning who don't under
don't understand why you're doing it
this way and that is one risk that you
need to take and you need to step out
and realize that that temporarily you
may have people that tell you wait that
doesn't look good that doesn't like you
should be doing this better and you got
to have blinders on and focus in on a
system that's proven that works and that
gets results and that's the system that
I teach to my clients that's the system
that we teach in this podcast and in the
live events that my host I I want to see
you succeed the only reason why I'm
saying this is for you to be successful
that's
it do you want to be financially
successful or not that's the choice that
you have to make
today and it very much hinges on your
ability to quote unquote stop doing all
of these things that you feel you must
do these they could even be best
practices that people tell you that you
need to do and yet they're the the most
detrimental thing that you could
possibly
do you might even feel strongly that
these are the right things to do and yet
they are what will prevent you from
financial
success most of all and one of the
biggest is people pleasing needing to
please others needing to make other
people happy operating the gambling
addiction mindset of pressing the slot
machine of other people's approval you
don't always win and sometimes you get
bit back but you you keep coming back
trying to make everybody happy and you
got to break up with people
pleasing you got to work on it you got
to figure out what can I work on
internally to stop operating this way
and to actually start to shift my
thinking out of reactivity and emotions
driving all of your choices I don't
recommend not feeling your emotions
that's important I don't recommend
stuffing them and putting them down I'm
saying that you get to decide what to do
your emotions don't make the choice for
you and that will help you succeed my
friends that's what working with a
therapist can do that's what working
with a counselor and even working on our
mental health can do as well and I
promise you that if you commit to
growing in every area of your life and
your business if you stay
consistent success will happen for you
it might not happen as quick as you want
it might not look like the path that you
expected
but sometimes what produces the results
we need come in the most unexpected
packages all right grow your life
everybody and we'll talk soon have a
good
[Applause]
[Music]
one